准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
痞宝辅食
代言记
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
稳着点  痞老板
Steady, Plankton
小心
Careful
厨房
吵什么吵
What is all that noise?
笑什么笑
What is so funny?
笑这个
This
这么多屁股
Hopping hineys
给我收起来
Put those away
少尴尬了
Don't be embarrassed
就只是你的宝宝照片而已
It's just your baby pictures
你那时真可爱
You were adorable
我从来都不可爱
I was never adorable
这些照片一个都不能留
These photos have got to go
你那时可真是个可爱的宝宝
You were such a cute baby
可爱到我受不了
I can't stand it
烂
Boo
我才不可可爱爱呢
I'm not cute and adorable
我可怕又邪恶
I'm horrifying and evil
痞老板可是我见过最可爱的宝宝
Plankton was the cutest baby I've ever seen
我一定要证明给他看
and I'm gonna prove it to him
也少让他遭罪了
Keeps him off the streets
该吃饭了  莫比
Time to eat, Moby
你一定会爱上这款全新鲸鱼宝宝辅食
You're gonna love this new whale baby food
名叫  鲸须宝贝
It's called Baleen Baby
宝贝
baby
张嘴
Open up
不要
No
拜托了  莫比
Come on, Moby
潜艇过来开进湖里了
Here comes the submarine into the lagoon
不要
No
爸爸
Da-Da
我要我的鲸须宝贝
I want my Baleen Baby
宝贝
baby
他叫我爸爸
He called me Da-Da
你的孩子会边叫你爸爸
Your kids will call you Da-Da
边嘎嘎品尝美味的鲸须宝贝
as they go ga-ga for the delicious taste of Baleen Baby
鲸须宝贝
宝贝
baby
现在要来公布是谁赢了
And now it's time to announce the winner
本次鲸须宝贝辅食的最可爱宝宝比赛
of Baleen Baby food's cutest baby contest
宝宝痞老板
Baby Plankton
海之霸
痞老板  你看
Plankton, look
海绵宝宝他没错
SpongeBob was right
我现在可没空听你废话  凯伦
I don't have time for malarkey now, Karen
机油刚刚都用光了
I just ran out of robot oil
敌
友
出口
宝宝痞老板的照片
Look for Baby Plankton's picture
每罐鲸须宝贝辅食上都找得到哦
on every jar of Baleen Baby baby food
鲸须宝贝
宝贝
Baby
他一定会爱上的
He's gonna love that
便宜货超市
他在那
There he is
就是他
It's him
真不敢相信
I can't believe it
天啊
Oh, man
不好意思
Pardon me
你先请
After you
我平常购物都会被别人踩的
People usually step on me when I'm shopping
奇怪
Strange
鲸须宝贝
机油
Robot oil
该开爬了
Time to get climbing
不用
Oh, no
让我来帮你拿
Let me get that for you
谢了
Thanks?
不用谢  小可爱
Anytime, cutie
我才不是小可爱
I am not a cutie
总共多少钱
Okay, what do I owe you?
不用钱的  先生
It's on the house, sir
因为你实在很
On account of you being so
出名
famous
获胜者
鲸须宝贝
臭名远扬才对吧  不过也罢
It's pronounced "infamous," but okay
祝你今天愉快
Have a nice day
我电视上看过那屁股
I seen that butt on the TV
我要我的鲸须宝贝
I want my Baleen Baby
宝贝
baby
什么动静
What was that?
屁股缝飞艇
Blimping butt cracks
来买鲸须宝贝
Buy some Baleen Baby
鲸须宝贝
凯伦
Karen
鲸须宝贝
你竟敢不经我允许传播我宝宝大头照
How dare you give out my baby mugshots
without my permission
虽然我很想邀功  谢尔顿
As much as I'd like to, Sheldon
但这种事不能赖在我头上
I can't take credit for this one
是我干的
I did it
这下你一定高兴坏了吧
Now aren't you happier knowing
毕竟你还是全裤头村最可爱的宝宝
that you're still the cutest baby in town?
个鬼
No
我要激发所有人心中的恐惧
I want to strike fear in the hearts of everyone
才不是要让老太婆捏我脸蛋
not make old ladies pinch my cheek
看我脸上的捏痕
Look at these pinch marks
看着就疼
That looks painful
真对不起  痞老板
Sorry about that, Plankton
傻子才道歉  海绵笨笨
Sorry is for suckers, SpongeBoob
你害得我因为宝宝照片搞得一团糟
You got me into this baby picture mess
就得帮我收拾干净
and you're gonna help me clean it up
我准备好了
I'm ready
鲸须宝贝
获胜者
计划如下
Here's the plan
把我所有的宝宝照片都盖住
We cover up all my baby pictures
明白
Got it
但是首先
But first
要砍掉广告牌
we chop down the billboards
然后往公交车广告撒油漆
Then, we paint over the bus ads
发射
Fire
我没事
I'm okay
便宜货超市
最后
And finally
把鲸须宝贝辅食存货全买了
we buy up the entire supply of Baleen Baby food
再埋到沙漠里
and bury it in the desert
天啊
Oh, boy
我们成功了
We did it
再也没谁会看我光身子的宝宝照片了
Nobody will ever see my naked baby photos again
那那  那什么玩意
Wh-wh-what the heck was that?
海海  海郊狼吗
S-s-sea coyotes?
就一群鲸鱼宝宝而已
It's just a bunch of whale babies
老可爱了
They're adorable
他们怎么那样子盯着我
Why are they staring at me like that?
多半是闻到宝宝辅食味了吧
They probably smell the baby food
话说鲸鱼宝宝都吃什么
What do baby whales eat anyway?
管他呢
Who cares?
扔一罐过去  赶他们走得了
Toss 'em a jar and make 'em go away
别闹了  宝宝们
Break it up, babies
别闹了
Break it up
鲸须宝贝辅食成分为百分之百的
"Baleen Baby food is made of 100%"
咽口水
"Gulp"?
你咽什么口水
What the heck is "gulp"?
百分之百的
"100%
浮浮浮  浮游生物
p-p-p-plankton"?
配料
100%
浮游生物
鲸须宝贝就是浮游生物
Baleen Baby is plankton
快跑
Run
他们都哪来的
Where are they all coming from?
不知道
I don't know
不过我还挺喜欢他们的鲸鱼歌
But I really dig their whale song
千万不要听  海绵宝宝
Don't listen, SpongeBob
据说鲸鱼宝宝的歌很有催眠效果
Some say the song of a baby whale is so hypnotic
会把你同化成凶狠贪食
it can turn you into a voracious
还爱吃浮游生物的
plankton-eating
鲸鱼
whale
我要找妈妈
I want my mama
海之霸
海神王啊
Sweet Neptune
A级海霸糊
海霸糊
Chum
我一定是打赌赌输了
I must have lost a bet
救命
Help
这下松了一口气
That's a relief
还以为你们要吃了
I thought you guys were gonna eat--
恶心
Yuck
宝宝们  不要碰痞老板哦
All right, babies, leave Plankton alone now
看他们对我触须干了什么好事  老妈
Look what they did to my antennas, Mommy
我到哪都认得那屁股
I'd know that hiney anywhere
是宝宝痞老板的明星屁股
Those are Baby Plankton's famous buns
我倒要来踹你屁股  怪东西
I'll kick your buns, you weirdo
我只是要来给你鲸须宝贝比赛奖金
I'm just here to give you the Baleen Baby contest check
收款人 痞老板
今天
备注 可爱
总共千千万万块
for one jillion dollars
宝贝
baby
那个
Well
这宝宝辅食的事就要另当别论了
that's a baby food of a different flavor
我接受
I accept
说什么
What's that?
宝宝痞老板味道像海霸糊
Baby Plankton tastes like chum?
这可不太利于生意
That's not gonna be good for business
好  改变计划
Okay, change of plans
不再跟这位独眼博士合作
We're done with Dr. Cyclops here
改用我们手上第二好的宝宝照片
so let's go with the second best baby photo we have
蟹堡王
怎么
What the
老螃蟹
Krabs?
对了
Oh yeah
我都忘了
I forgot
我还把蟹老板的宝宝照片寄过去了
I sent in Mr. Krabs' baby photo, too
说实话  还挺可爱
Actually, that's adorable
我好捏的脸蛋啊
My pinchable cheeks
小海绵
大灵感
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
抓到了
Tag
你当鬼
You're it
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你当鬼
You're it
不好意思
Excuse me
天才还在这边用功呢
Genius at work here
我的天啊
Oh, my golly
我的画
My painting
全毁了
It's ruined
你害我美丽的自画像成了一坨
You turned my beautiful self-portrait into a
一坨海绵
a sponge-blob
我觉得挺好看的
I think it looks good
就你懂什么  庶民
What do you know, plebeian?
得把这玩意扔到它该去的地方
This is going where it belongs
垃圾堆里
In the trash
这是个什么东西
What have we here?
大伙儿过来看
Fellas, check this out
我从未见过此般美丽的艺术品
I've never seen such a profoundly beautiful work of art
让我想起这混沌的世上
It reminds me that in this chaotic world
依旧有着毫不掩饰之美
there is still unabashed beauty
看吧
See?
大家都爱你的画
People love your painting
他们是收垃圾的  当然喜欢垃圾了
They're garbage people, of course they like garbage
提醒你一句
For your information
我们几个都有鲸鱼大学的艺术学位
we all got art degrees from Whale University
慢点跳  我的小心脏
Be still, my beating heart
这幅旷世巨作是谁画的
Who's responsible for this masterpiece?
我是佩吉石斑海姆  头号画商
I'm Peggy Grouperheim, big-time art dealer
你的画简直才华横溢
Your painting is a work of sheer genius
我要买下它
I'll buy it
你认可我的才华吗
You recognize my genius?
你要是喜欢呢
Well, if you like that
一定还会爱上我其他的画作
you're gonna love my other paintings
才不呢  亲爱的
Oh no, dear
那些玩意缺乏
Those lack the spark of
这幅画的活力
this painting
那个小鬼肯定就是你的灵感源泉
Clearly, that little urchin is your muse
给我多画几幅画  专门画他
Make me more paintings of him
到时候我会在我画廊里给你办特展
and I'll give you a show in my gallery
这是我名片
Here's my card
她居然真喜欢你的画啊  章鱼哥
She actually liked your painting, Squidward
对啊  她什么毛病
Yeah, what's wrong with her?
我专属的画廊特展
My own gallery show
我的名声马上就能响彻全世界了
Soon, the whole world will know me
而我出名的关键就是天分与艺术之魂
for my artistic soul, my genius
可我得画海绵宝宝
But I gotta paint SpongeBob
我根本就不想跟他共处同一片海洋
I don't even like being in the same ocean with him
完全没办法叫他给我摆姿势
I can't ask him to pose for me
等等
Wait
我真是个天才
I'm a genius
直接凭印象画他就好了
I'll just paint him from memory
我这么久都想忘掉海绵宝宝的存在
I've spent so long trying to forget SpongeBob exists
完全忘了他长什么样
I've forgotten what he looks like
只剩一个办法了
There's only one thing to do
偷偷摸摸地画
Stealth painting
蟹堡王
薯条做好了
Fries are ready
做得不好吃
Those fries are off
最好把这滚烫的热油给换了
I better change this boiling hot oil
下班时间到了
Quittin' time
该去滑浪学校了
Off to boating school
我来了  泡芙老师
I'm coming, Mrs. Puff
得来个更直接的办法
I need a more direct approach
水母田
美术不行
If fine arts aren't working
那就上武术
maybe martial arts will
他们可是我的孩子
Them's my kids
你  你不明白
You-you don't understand
可是  可是
But-but
该来个更直接上不少的办法了
Time for an even more direct approach
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你好  章鱼哥
Hello, Squidward--
画到了
Gotcha
你又做到了
You've done it again
又画出了一幅美丽的旷世巨作
Another beautiful masterpiece
继续与你的灵感源泉共事吧
Just keep working with your muse
遵命  女士
Yes, ma'am
我是你灵感源泉吗
I'm your muse?
别想太多了
Don't let it go to your head
章鱼哥  你要我摆姿势
Well, if you wanted me to pose, Squidward
直接问我就行了啊
all you had to do was ask
我愿意做任何事
I would do anything
帮你实现艺术美梦
to help you achieve your artistic dreams
真的吗
You would?
那当然
Of course
来画画吧
Now let's get painting
我要启发灵感
I'm musing
我要启发灵感  我要启发灵感
I'm musing, I'm musing
站到那上面去
Stand up there
一只手放你臀部
Now, put one hand on your hip
另一只举到半空中
and raise the other in the air
明白
Got it
你觉得这姿势行不行
What do you think about this pose?
选好姿势不要乱动
Just pick a pose and stay still
这个行不行
How about this?
都说了不要乱动
I said stay still
谢谢
Thank you
你没咋捕捉到我成熟又天真的品质啊
You haven't quite captured
my quality of mature naivete
你应该当我灵感源泉  不是批评我
You're supposed to be my muse, not my critic
这下我能画画了
Now I can paint
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
能往前挪一点点吗
Could you scoot forward?
没问题  章鱼哥
You got it, Squidward
不是我
That wasn't me
是椅子
That was the chair
海绵宝宝  麻烦不要乱动
SpongeBob, please stay still
有谁放屁了吗
Somebody step on a duck?
踩 鸭 子
再也受不了了
I can't take it anymore
看来章鱼哥不觉得我好笑
I guess Squidward didn't find me amusing
启发灵感
出口
是出口
The way out
来画灵感源泉
Paint the muse
对  章鱼哥
Yeah, Squidward
来画我
Paint me
永远永远永远画一辈子
Forever and ever and ever and ever
我这就画你
I'll paint you
马上就画死你
I'll paint you to oblivion
我要来画画了
Here I go a-painting
画画了  画画了
A-painting, a-painting
我要来画画了
Here I go a-painting
整天浑浑噩噩
All the ding-dong day
来让章鱼哥发大财
Time to make Squidward rich
顺便让我发更大的财
and me richer
天啊
Oh, dear
看来我又把一位艺术家逼得太紧了
Looks like I pushed another artist too hard
马上给他的旧画抬价
Mark up the prices of his old paintings
虽然我名气尽失
I may have lost all my fame
金钱也尽失
and money
不过起码  我又喜欢上画画了
but at least, I enjoy painting again
兄弟  你画完了没
Hey, buddy, you finished with that?
完了
Yes
那就好
Great
又有垃圾了
More garbage
果不其然
Typical